Hello, English learners.
你好，英语学习者。
Welcome back to another great lesson at EnglishPod.
欢迎回到 EnglishPod 的另一堂精彩课程。
My name is Marco.
我是 Marco。
And my name's Erica.
我是 Erica。
And today we're going to be building something.
今天我们要一起建造点东西。
That's right.
没错。
We've got a lesson about construction.
我们有一堂关于建筑的课程。
Cool.
酷。
So we're going to be working at a construction site today and we're going to learn a lot
所以今天我们要在建筑工地上工作，学习很多
of cool vocabulary with different types of tools.
关于不同类型工具的酷词汇。
And we'll also learn some phrases that you can use to talk about work.
我们还会学到一些可以用来谈论工作的短语。
So even if you're not really interested in building and making stuff with your hands,
所以即使你对亲手建造和制作东西不太感兴趣，
you will learn some language to talk about work in general.
你也会学到一些一般谈论工作的语言。
All right.
好的。
So before we get started with this construction dialogue, let's take a look at vocabulary
在我们开始这段建筑对话之前，让我们先看一下词汇
preview.
预览。
Vocabulary preview.
词汇预览。
Well, Marco, we're going to look at two words now.
嗯，Marco，我们现在要看两个词。
And like you said, we're building something in this lesson, right?
就像你说的，这节课我们要建造点东西，对吧？
Right.
对。
We're going to be building a deck.
我们要建一个露台。
A deck.
一个露台。
All right.
好的。
So a deck.
所以是露台。
What is that?
那是什么？
Basically, it's an elevated wooden platform that houses will have like in their backyards
基本上，它是一个高架的木质平台，房子通常在后院会有
maybe.
那种。
So it's a platform that's a little bit higher off the ground behind your house.
所以它是一个比地面稍高一点的平台，在房子后面。
So it's very popular for houses to have decks and people will put out a table and chairs
所以房子有露台很常见，人们会放上桌子和椅子，
and maybe have lunch out there or something.
也许在那里吃午饭什么的。
Or barbecue or something.
或者烧烤什么的。
Exactly.
没错。
Yeah.
是的。
Okay.
好的。
So a deck.
所以是露台。
Now, they're building this deck and they need to follow some plans.
现在，他们在建这个露台，需要遵循一些图纸。
Plans.
图纸。
The plans that we're talking about are construction plans.
我们说的图纸是建筑图纸。
Yeah.
是的。
It's kind of like the map for the deck.
它有点像露台的地图。
How you're going to build it.
你要怎么建它。
Exactly.
没错。
So we can have floor plans, for example.
所以我们可以有平面图，例如。
So that shows you how the building looks like where the different rooms are.
那会显示建筑的样子，不同房间在哪里。
Like a house, right?
就像房子，对吧？
So it's basically the map for a construction.
所以它基本上是建筑的地图。
Okay, great.
好的，很好。
So two interesting words.
所以是两个有趣的词。
We're going to hear both of these in the dialogue.
我们会在对话中听到这两个词。
Now why don't we get started and find out what's going to happen as they're building
现在我们为什么不开始，看看他们在建这个
this deck.
露台时会发生什么。
All right, ladies and gentlemen, we've been hired to build a deck on this here house and
好的，女士们先生们，我们被雇来在这栋房子上建一个露台，把
turn this boring and drab lawn into a backyard oasis.
这个无聊单调的草坪变成一个后院绿洲。
There is one catch though.
但有一个条件。
We've only got one day to finish this.
我们只有一天时间完成这个。
So I'm going to need everyone to give 110% today.
所以我需要今天每个人都付出110%的努力。
It's going to be tough, but we've got a great team here and I know that together we can
这会很艰难，但我们有一个很棒的团队，我知道我们一起可以
tackle this project.
应对这个项目。
That being said, let's get to work.
话虽如此，我们开始工作吧。
That's right.
没错。
Now remember, we've been over the plans, but we really need to make sure that everything
现在记住，我们已经看过图纸了，但我们真的需要确保一切
is up to code.
都符合规范。
The home inspectors here are pretty thorough.
这里的房屋检查员很彻底。
So please make sure you follow the plans exactly.
所以请确保你严格按照图纸操作。
And remember the carpenter's rule of thumb, measure twice, cut once.
记住木匠的经验法则：量两次，切一次。
Okay, guys, let's get at it.
好了，伙计们，开始干吧。
Bob, pass me that hammer.
Bob，把那个锤子递给我。
The nails won't go in.
钉子钉不进去。
The wood is too hard.
木头太硬了。
I think I'm going to need the nail gun.
我想我需要钉枪。
That did it.
搞定了。
Hey, do me a favor and help me cut this two by four, will you?
嘿，帮我个忙，帮我切这块二乘四的木头，好吗？
Pass me that circle saw and grab hold of the end of the board.
把那个圆锯递给我，抓住木板的一端。
Now help me drill some holes in it so we can place the bolts.
现在帮我钻几个洞，这样我们可以放螺栓。
I think you should sand the edges.
我觉得你应该打磨边缘。
Look at all these splinters.
看看这些木刺。
Someone could get hurt.
有人可能会受伤。
Geez, you've got to take pride in your work.
天哪，你得对自己的工作有自豪感。
Yeah, you're right.
是的，你说得对。
Pass me the sander and I'll take care of it.
把打磨机递给我，我来处理。
Julia, get over here with that level, measuring tape, and that box of screws.
Julia，过来，带上那个水平仪、卷尺和那盒螺丝。
Oh no, look out below.
哦不，下面的人小心。
All right, so there are a lot of people building the deck.
好的，所以有很多人在建露台。
They have to build it fast.
他们必须建得很快。
They've only got one day.
他们只有一天时间。
So it's a really big challenge, huh?
所以这是一个很大的挑战，是吧？
Yeah, and I think this is a good lesson in maybe not rushing through important projects,
是的，我认为这堂课是一个很好的教训，也许不要匆忙完成重要项目，
right?
对吧？
Exactly.
没错。
So we saw some really interesting tools that they were using.
所以我们看到了一些他们使用的非常有趣的工具。
So why don't we look at that first in Language Takeaway.
那我们为什么不先看看语言要点里的内容。
Language Takeaway.
语言要点。
All right, so we've got some language all about tools.
好的，所以我们有一些关于工具的语言。
So why don't we just get started?
那我们为什么不直接开始呢？
So they mentioned a nail gun.
所以他们提到了钉枪。
Nail gun.
钉枪。
A nail gun.
一把钉枪。
So we all know about hammers and nails, right?
我们都知道锤子和钉子，对吧？
Right.
对。
So the nails are what you put in the wood.
所以钉子是你钉进木头里的东西。
Exactly.
没错。
Now this is an advanced tool, so you don't have to use a hammer.
现在这是一个高级工具，所以你不需要用锤子。
It's kind of hard to explain, so why don't we listen to the sound this tool makes.
这有点难解释，所以我们为什么不听听这个工具发出的声音。
Well, I guess like its name suggests, it's a gun for putting nails in wood.
嗯，我想就像它的名字暗示的那样，它是一种把钉子钉进木头的枪。
Yeah, it actually uses compressed air to push nails really fast into the wood.
是的，它实际上用压缩空气把钉子快速推进木头里。
All right.
好的。
All right, so they are nailing some pieces of wood together, but they also needed to
好的，所以他们正在把一些木头钉在一起，但他们也需要
cut the wood, and they said, help me cut the two by four.
切割木头，他们说，帮我切这块二乘四的木头。
Yeah, she said, help me cut this two by four.
是的，她说，帮我切这块二乘四的木头。
So a two by four.
所以是二乘四的木头。
This is a very popular type of wood that you use in construction.
这是一种在建筑中非常常用的木头。
A two by four is basically two inches by four inches.
二乘四基本上就是两英寸乘四英寸。
So two inches high and four inches wide.
所以两英寸高，四英寸宽。
So it's the most popular and common type of wood that you would use for construction,
所以这是建筑中最常用和最常见的木头类型，
a two by four.
二乘四的木头。
You'll hear it all the time.
你会经常听到它。
So they're going to cut the two by four, and C said, pass me the circular saw.
所以他们要切这块二乘四的木头，C说，把圆锯递给我。
A circular saw.
一把圆锯。
So a saw, we understand, is something you use to cut wood, but you have many types of
所以锯子，我们理解，是用来切割木头的东西，但有很多种
saws.
锯子。
You have a band saw, you have a circular saw, and this one makes this sound.
有带锯，有圆锯，这个会发出这种声音。
So I guess it's called a circular saw because the blade or the cutting part is shaped in
所以我猜它叫圆锯是因为刀片或切割部分是圆形的。
a circle.
是的，一把圆锯。
Yeah, a circular saw.
So after they cut the piece of wood, one of the guys said, I think you should sand the
所以在他们切完那块木头后，其中一个人说，我觉得你应该打磨
edges.
边缘。
To sand something.
打磨某物。
All right.
好的。
So if you want to sand usually a piece of wood, you want to use paper covered in sand
所以如果你想打磨通常一块木头，你想用覆盖着沙子的纸
to make it very smooth.
让它变得非常光滑。
Yeah, exactly.
是的，没错。
And so they also mentioned a sander, right?
所以他们也提到了打磨机，对吧？
A sander is basically a machine that has this sandpaper on it and will do the hard work
打磨机基本上是一种机器，上面有砂纸，会为你做辛苦的
for you.
工作。
All right.
好的。
So to sand something and a sander.
所以是打磨某物和打磨机。
Now our next word is very related to sanding something because if you don't sand a piece
现在我们的下一个词和打磨某物非常相关，因为如果你不打磨一块
of wood, it might have splinters.
木头，它可能会有木刺。
Splinters.
木刺。
Splinter.
Splinters.
木刺。
So like I said, if you cut a piece of wood, there are little pieces of wood that stick
所以就像我说的，如果你切一块木头，会有小木片突出来，
out and you can get hurt.
你可能会受伤。
They can get under your skin.
它们会扎进你的皮肤。
Yeah.
是的。
So tiny, tiny parts of wood.
所以是非常非常小的木头碎片。
That's called a splinter.
那叫木刺。
A splinter.
木刺。
Okay.
好的。
So why don't we go on to our next tool.
那我们为什么不继续看下一个工具。
They were talking about a level.
他们在谈论水平仪。
A level.
水平仪。
The level.
All right.
好的。
So this is a tool that all carpenters have and it's basically a tool that has a little
所以这是所有木匠都有的工具，它基本上是一个里面有一点
bit of water in it, right?
水的工具，对吧？
Yeah.
是的。
And it helps you make sure that everything is straight and flat.
它帮助你确保一切都是水平和直的。
Exactly.
没错。
So that's a level.
所以那是水平仪。
Every carpenter has it.
每个木匠都有它。
And also a measuring tape.
还有卷尺。
A measuring tape.
卷尺。
Measuring tape.
Now I'm sure if this was a video podcast, we could show you what a measuring tape was
现在我确定如果这是一个视频播客，我们可以给你看卷尺是什么，
and you'd really understand it, but we'll do our best to describe it for you.
你会真正理解它，但我们会尽力为你描述。
So a measuring tape is like a ruler that rolls up.
所以卷尺就像一把可以卷起来的尺子。
Yeah.
是的。
It's a very convenient ruler because it can roll up and you can measure something that
它是一个非常方便的尺子，因为它可以卷起来，你可以测量
is maybe six feet or three meters long and you can extend it.
可能六英尺或三米长的东西，你可以把它拉长。
And when you're done measuring, you can put it back and just put it in your pocket.
当你量完后，你可以把它收回去，放进口袋。
Yeah.
是的。
Every carpenter has one.
每个木匠都有一个。
A measuring tape.
卷尺。
All right.
好的。
So that's our last tool that we're going to talk about.
所以那是我们要谈论的最后一个工具。
So why don't we move on now to Fluency Builder where we've got some phrases that you can
那我们为什么不继续到流利度构建部分，那里有一些你可以
use to talk about work.
用来谈论工作的短语。
Fluency Builder.
流利度构建。
So when the contractor started giving them instructions, he said, I need everyone to
所以当承包商开始给他们指示时，他说，我需要今天每个人都
give 110% today.
付出110%的努力。
To give 110%.
So when you give 110%, you are basically trying very hard.
所以当你付出110%的努力时，你基本上是在非常努力。
Yeah.
是的。
You give everything you have to your job.
你把所有的一切都投入到工作中。
Right.
对。
So it's not only 100%, it's 110, more than what's needed.
所以不仅仅是100%，而是110%，比需要的更多。
So no lunch break.
所以没有午休。
Exactly.
没错。
So as they were talking about the instructions, one of the guys said, the carpenter's rule
所以当他们谈论指示时，其中一个人说，木匠的
of thumb.
经验法则。
A rule of thumb.
So this is an interesting phrase, rule of thumb.
所以这是一个有趣的短语，经验法则。
What does that mean exactly?
那到底是什么意思？
Okay.
好的。
Well, you know what?
嗯，你知道吗？
I think we can understand the meaning pretty clearly if we listen to some examples.
我想如果我们听一些例子，我们可以很清楚地理解它的意思。
Example one.
例子一。
The rule of thumb in making a sale is confidence.
销售中的经验法则是自信。
Without confidence, you don't make a sale.
没有自信，你就做不成生意。
Example two.
例子二。
The tailor's rule of thumb is twice the circumference of the wrist is the circumference of the neck.
裁缝的经验法则是手腕周长的两倍等于脖子周长。
Example three.
例子三。
You don't have to take everything I say about marketing as a rule of thumb.
你不必把我说的所有关于营销的话都当作经验法则。
One of the guys noticed a few problems, you know, the splinters, and he said, you've got
其中一个人注意到了一些问题，比如那些木刺，然后他说，你做事得
to take pride in your work.
有自豪感。
Okay.
好的。
He said to take pride in your work.
他说做事要有自豪感。
To take pride in your work.
做事要有自豪感。
Why did he say that to her?
他为什么对她说这个？
What is he trying to tell her?
他想告诉她什么？
Well, because she made some mistakes, she didn't do such a good job.
嗯，因为她犯了一些错误，活儿干得不太好。
He's wanting her to work harder, work better, work more carefully.
他希望她更努力、做得更好、更仔细。
Okay.
好的。
And so she can be proud of her work and say, this is a job well done.
这样她才能为自己的工作感到自豪，说这是一份干得漂亮的活儿。
So when you take pride in your work, you work so well and do such a good job that you feel
所以当你为自己的工作感到自豪时，你会干得非常好，做得如此出色，以至于你感到
really happy about it.
非常开心。
All right.
好的。
Good.
很好。
So why don't we listen to this dialogue again for the last time and then we'll come back
那我们最后再听一遍这段对话，然后回来
and talk about construction.
聊聊建筑方面的事。
All right, ladies and gentlemen, we've been hired to build a deck on this here house and
好了，女士们先生们，我们被雇来在这栋房子上建一个露台，把
turn this boring and drab lawn into a backyard oasis.
这个单调乏味的草坪变成后院绿洲。
There is one catch though.
但有一个条件。
We've only got one day to finish this.
我们只有一天时间完成这个任务。
So I'm going to need everyone to give 110% today.
所以我需要大家今天付出百分之百的努力。
It's going to be tough, but we've got a great team here and I know that together we can
会很辛苦，但我们有一个很棒的团队，我知道只要我们齐心协力，就能
tackle this project.
搞定这个项目。
That being said, let's get to work.
话不多说，我们开工吧。
That's right.
没错。
Now remember, we've been over the plans, but we really need to make sure that everything
记住，我们已经看过图纸了，但我们真的需要确保一切
is up to code.
都符合规范。
The home inspectors here are pretty thorough.
这里的房屋检查员非常严格。
So please make sure you follow the plans exactly.
所以请务必严格按照图纸施工。
And remember the carpenters rule of thumb, measure twice, cut once.
记住木匠的经验法则：量两次，切一次。
Okay, guys, let's get at it.
好了，伙计们，开始干吧。
Bob pass me that hammer.
鲍勃，把那个锤子递给我。
The nails won't go in.
钉子钉不进去。
Wood is too hard.
木头太硬了。
I think I'm going to need the nail gun.
我想我需要用钉枪。
That did it.
搞定了。
Hey, do me a favor and help me cut this two by four, will ya?
嘿，帮我个忙，把这根二乘四的木头锯开，行吗？
Pass me that circle saw and grab hold of the end of the board.
把那个圆锯递给我，然后抓住木板的末端。
Now help me drill some holes in it so we can place the bolts.
现在帮我钻几个孔，这样我们就能放螺栓了。
I think you should sand the edges.
我觉得你应该把边缘打磨一下。
Look at all these splinters.
看看这些木刺。
One could get hurt.
会伤到人的。
Jeez, you got to take pride in your work.
天哪，你做事得有自豪感。
Yeah, you're right.
是啊，你说得对。
Pass me the sander and I'll take care of it.
把打磨机递给我，我来处理。
Julia, get over here with that level measuring tape and that box of screws.
朱莉娅，拿着水平尺和那盒螺丝过来。
Oh no, look out below.
哦不，下面的人小心。
So an interesting aspect of North American culture is projects like this, right?
北美文化中一个有趣的方面就是这样的项目，对吧？
Building a deck or maybe adding a room to your house.
比如建个露台或者给房子加个房间。
Yeah, that's right.
是的，没错。
And we call this DIY.
我们称之为DIY。
Right, DIY, do it yourself.
对，DIY，自己动手做。
So it's a very popular summer project, right?
所以这是一个很受欢迎的夏季项目，对吧？
Right.
对。
So if you live in a neighborhood in North America, you might see like, you know, the
所以如果你住在北美的一个社区，你可能会看到，比如，
dad of a family outside building something and all his friends come over and they, you
一家之主在外面建东西，他所有的朋友都过来，他们
know, drink beer and build this big thing together.
喝啤酒，一起建这个大东西。
Right.
对。
So it could be a tree house, it could be a deck, it could even maybe be adding another
所以可能是树屋，可能是露台，甚至可能是给房子
room to the house.
加个房间。
Yeah.
嗯。
And you know, it's actually, it's so popular that there are tons of TV shows about how
而且你知道吗，实际上，它非常受欢迎，以至于有大量关于如何
to build stuff for your house.
为房子建东西的电视节目。
And there are a lot of really big stores where you can go and find like all of this equipment
还有很多大型商店，你可以去那里找到所有
for building stuff for your house.
建房子用的设备。
Right.
对。
So basically there are these big stores where you can get anything from paint to wood to
所以基本上有这些大型商店，你可以买到从油漆到木材到
tools, huge amount of material so you can do it yourself.
工具的各种东西，大量的材料，这样你就可以自己动手。
You can DIY.
你可以DIY。
All right.
好的。
So that's all the time we have for today but let us know what you think and tell us if
这就是我们今天的所有时间了，但请告诉我们你的想法，并告诉我们
you are into doing handiwork like this, like maybe building a tree house or building a
你是否喜欢做这样的手工活，比如建树屋或
deck.
建露台。
That's right.
没错。
You can come to our website at EnglishPod.com and tell us about it.
你可以访问我们的网站EnglishPod.com，告诉我们。
As well, you can also leave your questions there.
同样，你也可以在那里留下你的问题。
All right.
好的。
So we'll see you guys there and until next time.
那我们就在那里见，下次再见。
Thanks for listening and goodbye.
感谢收听，再见。
Bye.
再见。